<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Descriptive Analysis on Onur Altindag</title>
    <link>https://onuraltindag.info/categories/descriptive-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Descriptive Analysis on Onur Altindag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>©2023 Onur Altındağ · Cover photo: Bayt Beirut, 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onuraltindag.info/categories/descriptive-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Information on Measles, Mumps and Rubella Vaccine in the Copenhagen School Health Records Register</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/denmark_mmr_chsr-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/denmark_mmr_chsr-/</guid>
      <description>Under review</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Humanitarian Aid Using Administrative Data: Model Design and Validation</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_targeting/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We develop and assess the performance of an econometric prediction model that relies on administrative data held by international agencies to target over $380 million annually in unconditional cash transfers to Syrian refugees in Lebanon. Standard metrics of prediction accuracy suggest targeting using administrative data is comparable to a short-form Proxy Means Test, which requires a survey of the entire target population. We show that small differences in accuracy across approaches are largely attributable to a few data fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judicial Bypass for Minors Obtaining an Abortion: Ten years of Data from Arkansas</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/arkansas_judicial_bypass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/arkansas_judicial_bypass/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Objectives. To describe demographic characteristics and abortion timing of minors in Arkansas who obtained an abortion through a judicial bypass, and to contrast the frequency of judicial bypass in other states in the United States.
Methods.We used individual-level data on all abortions to minors (n = 2624) performed in Arkansas from 2005 to 2014 and aggregated data from 10 additional states on abortions obtained through a judicial bypass. We characterized correlates of the judicial bypass and its association with the timing of abortion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
