<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Regression discontinuity design on Onur Altindag</title>
    <link>https://onuraltindag.info/categories/regression-discontinuity-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Regression discontinuity design on Onur Altindag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>©2023 Onur Altındağ · Cover photo: Bayt Beirut, 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onuraltindag.info/categories/regression-discontinuity-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Short-lived Effects of Unconditional Cash Transfers to Refugees</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_rd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_rd/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We study two yearlong unconditional cash-based assistance programs for Syrian refugees in Lebanon, and show that they improve consumption, child well-being, food security, and reduce livelihood coping. Despite high transfer values, we find no evidence of lasting effects at six months after either program ends. Households spend transfers on basic needs, and take children out of work and re-enroll them in school. Beneficiaries increase cash savings and their stock of durable goods, but liquidate and spend these assets during or soon after the beneficiary period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Health Costs of Lockdowns: Evidence from Age-Specific Curfews in Turkey</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_curfew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_curfew/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Using a strict, age-specific lockdown order for adults aged 65 and older in Turkey, we examine the mental health consequences of an extended period of tight mobility restrictions on senior adults. Adopting a regression discontinuity design, we find that the curfew-induced decline in mobility substantially worsened mental health outcomes, including somatic and nonsomatic symptoms of mental distress (approximately 0.2 standard deviation). Exploring potential channels, we document an increase in social and physical isolation, with no evidence of robust changes in labor market outcomes or intrahousehold conflict for this subpopulation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
