<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Regression Discontinuity Design on Onur Altindag</title>
    <link>https://onuraltindag.info/categories/regression-discontinuity-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Regression Discontinuity Design on Onur Altindag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>©2023 Onur Altındağ · Cover photo: Bayt Beirut, 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onuraltindag.info/categories/regression-discontinuity-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Short-lived Effects of Unconditional Cash Transfers to Refugees</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_rd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_rd/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We study two yearlong unconditional cash-based assistance programs for Syrian refugees in Lebanon, and show that they improve consumption, child well-being, food security, and reduce livelihood coping. Despite high transfer values, we find no evidence of lasting effects at six months after either program ends. Households spend transfers on basic needs, and take children out of work and re-enroll them in school. Beneficiaries increase cash savings and their stock of durable goods, but liquidate and spend these assets during or soon after the beneficiary period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Health Policy At Scale: Impact of a Government-sponsored Information Campaign on Infant Mortality in Denmark</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/denmark_sids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/denmark_sids/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We evaluate the impact of a nationwide public health intervention on deaths from sudden infant death syndrome (SIDS), using population data from Denmark in a regression discontinuity research design. The information campaign—implemented primarily through a universal nurse home visiting program—reduced infant mortality by 17.2 percent and saved between 11.6-13.5 lives over 10,000 births. The estimated effect sizes are 11-14 times larger among low birthweight and preterm infants relative to the overall population.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
