<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Onur Altındağ on Onur Altindag</title>
    <link>https://onuraltindag.info/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Onur Altındağ on Onur Altindag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>©2023 Onur Altındağ · Cover photo: Bayt Beirut, 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onuraltindag.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ADRD, Family Caregiving and Children’s Labor Supply in Denmark</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/project/adrd_denmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/project/adrd_denmark/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Research in progress.
Click here to download the full study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Well-being Measurement in Targeting Social Protection Programs</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/project/poverty_targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/project/poverty_targeting/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Research in progress.
Click here to download the full study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity, Integration, and Business Productivity</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/project/antep_sme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/project/antep_sme/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Research in progress.
Click here to download the full study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Uphill Battle to Restore Democracy</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/elections2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/elections2023/</guid>
      <description>In less than 50 days, on May 14, Turkey will hold a pivotal election, with both presidential and parliamentary seats up for grabs. After 20 years of President Erdogan’s Islamist party’s rule, the united opposition has a real chance to unseat him and his party. While the presidential election has garnered much attention, the parliamentary race is just as crucial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information on Measles, Mumps and Rubella Vaccine in the Copenhagen School Health Records Register</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/denmark_mmr_chsr-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/denmark_mmr_chsr-/</guid>
      <description>Under review</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Short-lived Effects of Unconditional Cash Transfers to Refugees</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_rd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_rd/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We study two yearlong unconditional cash-based assistance programs for Syrian refugees in Lebanon, and show that they improve consumption, child well-being, food security, and reduce livelihood coping. Despite high transfer values, we find no evidence of lasting effects at six months after either program ends. Households spend transfers on basic needs, and take children out of work and re-enroll them in school. Beneficiaries increase cash savings and their stock of durable goods, but liquidate and spend these assets during or soon after the beneficiary period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Day, Another Visit: Impact of Arkansas&#39; Mandatory Waiting Period for Women Seeking an Abortion by Demographic Groups</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/arkansas_abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/arkansas_abortion/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Twenty-six states require that women seeking an abortion wait between 18 and 72 h after receipt of counseling before the abortion can be completed. Thirteen states require that the counseling be given in person necessitating at least two visits to the provider. In April of 2015, Arkansas increased the waiting period for an abortion from 24 to 48 h and more significantly, required that women receive the counseling in person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Health Policy At Scale: Impact of a Government-sponsored Information Campaign on Infant Mortality in Denmark</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/denmark_sids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/denmark_sids/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We evaluate the impact of a nationwide public health intervention on deaths from sudden infant death syndrome (SIDS), using population data from Denmark in a regression discontinuity research design. The information campaign—implemented primarily through a universal nurse home visiting program—reduced infant mortality by 17.2 percent and saved between 11.6-13.5 lives over 10,000 births. The estimated effect sizes are 11-14 times larger among low birthweight and preterm infants relative to the overall population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Health Costs of Lockdowns: Evidence from Age-Specific Curfews in Turkey</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_curfew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_curfew/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Using a strict, age-specific lockdown order for adults aged 65 and older in Turkey, we examine the mental health consequences of an extended period of tight mobility restrictions on senior adults. Adopting a regression discontinuity design, we find that the curfew-induced decline in mobility substantially worsened mental health outcomes, including somatic and nonsomatic symptoms of mental distress (approximately 0.2 standard deviation). Exploring potential channels, we document an increase in social and physical isolation, with no evidence of robust changes in labor market outcomes or intrahousehold conflict for this subpopulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do refugees impact voting behavior in the host country? Evidence from Syrian refugee inflows to Turkey</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_refugees_voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_refugees_voting/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We study how individual political preferences changed in response to the influx of over 3.5 million Syrian refugees to Turkey during 2012–2016. Using a difference-in-differences research design, we compare the political outcomes in geographic areas with high versus low intensities of refugee presence before and after the beginning of the Syrian Civil War. To address the endogeneity of refugees’ location choices, we adopt an instrumental variables approach that relies on (1) historical dispersion of Arabic speakers in Turkish provinces and (2) driving distances between Turkish and Syrian residential areas to predict the flows of refugees across Turkish provinces during the study period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Humanitarian Aid Using Administrative Data: Model Design and Validation</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_targeting/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We develop and assess the performance of an econometric prediction model that relies on administrative data held by international agencies to target over $380 million annually in unconditional cash transfers to Syrian refugees in Lebanon. Standard metrics of prediction accuracy suggest targeting using administrative data is comparable to a short-form Proxy Means Test, which requires a survey of the entire target population. We show that small differences in accuracy across approaches are largely attributable to a few data fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blessing or burden? Impacts of refugees on businesses and the informal economy</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_refugees_firms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_refugees_firms/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We study the impact of the sudden arrival of more than three million Syrian refugees in Turkey on Turkish businesses. Our empirical methodology exploits the annual variation in refugee outflows from Syria and geographic concentrations of Arabic-speaking communities in Turkey, which date back to the rupture of the Ottoman Empire after World War I. Using yearly firm census data from 2006 to 2015, we document that refugee inflows induced a positive impact on the intensive and extensive margins of firm production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karantinanın ruh sağlığına etkileri</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/karantina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/karantina/</guid>
      <description>Covid-19 ile  mücadele için alınan önlemler arasında psikolojik olarak belki de en ağır olanı karantina. Karantina yüksek risk grubundaki bireyleri daha fazla etkiliyor. Bu grup pandemi boyunca daha az hareket ediyor ve sosyal olarak kendini daha çok izole ediyor. Bu bireylerin mevcut sağlık durumunu toplum genelinden halihazırda daha kötü olduğu için,  hareketsizlik ve sosyal izolasyonun fiziksel ve ruh sağlığına etkisi daha da riskli bir konuma evriliyor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koronavirüs vefat sayıları ne anlatıyor?</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/excess_mortality_tr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/excess_mortality_tr/</guid>
      <description>Hepimizin takip ettiği ve Sağlık Bakanlığı tarafından açıklanan koronovirüs bağlantılı ölüm sayıları, tıbbi testlerle virüsü taşıdığı teyit edilmiş hastaların vefatlarını yansıtıyor. Türkiye de diğer ülkeler gibi tanı konmadan vefat etmiş hastaları bu istatistiklere dahil etmiyor. Bu nedenle, direkt ya da dolaylı yoldan koronavirüs nedeniyle ölen hasta sayısı, beyan edilen rakamların üstünde.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do official COVID19 death statistics tell us?</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/excess_mortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/excess_mortality/</guid>
      <description>The Turkish Ministry of Health announces the death toll due to novel coronavirus cases on a daily basis. These statistics are based on confirmed COVID19 cases. Like other countries, Turkey does not include people who died without proper medical diagnoses into the official statistics. As such, the number of patients who died directly or indirectly due to COVID19 tend to be higher than the numbers in official statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Nonexperimental Methods Provide Unbiased Estimates of a Breastfeeding Intervention? A Within-Study Comparison of Peer Counseling in Oregon</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/oregon_non_experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/oregon_non_experiment/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Between July 2005 and July 2007, the Oregon Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants and Children program conducted the largest randomized field experiment (RFE) ever in the United States to assess the effectiveness of a low-cost peer counseling intervention to promote exclusive breastfeeding. We undertook a within-study comparison of the intervention using unique administrative data between July 2005 and July 2010. We found no difference between experimental and nonexperimental estimates but failed to determine correspondence based on more stringent criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of the Affordable Care Act Medicaid Expansion on Subjective Well-Being in the US Adult Population, 2010–2016</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/aca_medicaid_subjective_wellbeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/aca_medicaid_subjective_wellbeing/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Objectives. To determine whether the 2014 Affordable Care Act Medicaid expansion affected well-being in the low-income and general adult US populations. Methods. We obtained data from adults aged 18 to 64 years in the nationally representative Gallup-Sharecare Well-Being Index from 2010 to 2016 (n = 1 674 953). We used a difference-in-differences analysis to compare access to and difficulty affording health care and subjective well-being outcomes (happiness, sadness, worry, stress, and life satisfaction) before and after Medicaid expansion in states that did and did not expand Medicaid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judicial Bypass for Minors Obtaining an Abortion: Ten years of Data from Arkansas</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/arkansas_judicial_bypass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/arkansas_judicial_bypass/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Objectives. To describe demographic characteristics and abortion timing of minors in Arkansas who obtained an abortion through a judicial bypass, and to contrast the frequency of judicial bypass in other states in the United States.
Methods.We used individual-level data on all abortions to minors (n = 2624) performed in Arkansas from 2005 to 2014 and aggregated data from 10 additional states on abortions obtained through a judicial bypass. We characterized correlates of the judicial bypass and its association with the timing of abortion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Measuring and Reducing Selection Bias With a Quasi-Doubly Randomized Preference Trial</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/baruch_drpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/baruch_drpt/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Randomized experiments provide unbiased estimates of treatment effects, but are costly and time consuming. We demonstrate how a randomized experiment can be leveraged to measure selection bias by conducting a subsequent observational study that is identical in every way except that subjects choose their treatment—a quasi-doubly randomized preference trial (quasi-DRPT). Researchers first strive to think of and measure all possible confounders and then determine how well these confounders as controls can reduce or eliminate selection bias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Son Preference, Fertility Decline, and the Nonmissing Girls of Turkey</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_son_preference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_son_preference/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Couples in Turkey exhibit son preference through son-biased differential stopping behavior that does not cause a sex ratio imbalance in the population. Demand for sons leads to lower ratios of boys to girls in larger families but higher ratios in smaller families. Girls are born earlier than their male siblings, and son-biased fertility behavior is persistent in response to decline in fertility over time and across households with parents from different backgrounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does classroom time matter?</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/baruch_rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/baruch_rct/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Little experimental evidence exists on the causal impact of class time on academic performance when students have access to extensive course material online. We randomized 725 college students into traditional twice-per-week and compressed once-per-week lecture formats in introductory microeconomics. Students in the traditional format scored 3.2 out of 100 points higher (0.21 standard deviations) on the midterm than those in the compressed format but a statistically insignificant 1.6 points higher (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telephone peer counseling of breastfeeding among WIC participants: a randomized controlled trial</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/oregon_rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/oregon_rct/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We develop and assess the performance of an econometric prediction model that relies on administrative data held by international agencies to target over $380 million annually in unconditional cash transfers to Syrian refugees in Lebanon. Standard metrics of prediction accuracy suggest targeting using administrative data is comparable to a short-form Proxy Means Test, which requires a survey of the entire target population. We show that small differences in accuracy across approaches are largely attributable to a few data fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownbag program</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/brownbag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/brownbag/</guid>
      <description>Bentley University Economics Department Brown Bag Seminar Series Wednesday, May 31 2023 - SMI 203 Program 9 am Coffee &amp;amp; Pastries 9:15 am Introductions 9:30 am The Building Blocks of Inflation: the Role of Monetary policy and the Gap between Goods and Services Sacha Gelfer 10:15 am Asymmetric effects of monetary policy on firms Ezgi Kurt 11:00 am Time-Varying Volatility of International Stock Returns Laura Coroneo, Laura Jackson, Michael Owyang 11:50 am Lunch 1:00 pm Family Caregiving and Labor Supply: Evidence from Deaths in Denmark Onur Altindag, Jane Greve and Yulya Truskinovsky 1:45 pm Retainer-Based (Concierge) Medicine and Two-Part Tariffs Ben Chartock and Patrick Scholten 2:30 pm Can the Endowment Effect Distort the Outcome of Prediction Markets?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/contact/</guid>
      <description>⛩ AAC Room 181, 175 Forest St, Waltham, MA 02452. ✎ oaltindag@bentley.edu ☎ +1.781.216.7111
💻 Schedule office hours - 30 min</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Community</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/colleagues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/colleagues/</guid>
      <description>My heartfelt appreciation goes out to all my co-authors who have shared their intellectual, technical, and creative skills in support of our past and ongoing projects:
Matvei Andersen Jennifer Lyn Baker Ozan Bakış Zeynep Balcıoğlu Ceren Baysan Lisa Berkman Sean Crockett Bilge Erten Aimee Kunze Foong Jane Greve Matilda Jerneck David Jaeger Ted Joyce Lindsay Kobayashi Neeraj Kaushal Pınar Keskin Stephen D. O&amp;rsquo;Connell Julie Reeder Dahlia Remler Sandra Rozo Lucie Schmidt Purvi Sevak Aytuğ Şaşmaz Erdal Tekin Yulya Truskinovsky </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
