<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Randomized Experiment on Onur Altindag</title>
    <link>https://onuraltindag.info/categories/randomized-experiment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Randomized Experiment on Onur Altindag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>©2023 Onur Altındağ · Cover photo: Bayt Beirut, 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onuraltindag.info/categories/randomized-experiment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can Nonexperimental Methods Provide Unbiased Estimates of a Breastfeeding Intervention? A Within-Study Comparison of Peer Counseling in Oregon</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/oregon_non_experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/oregon_non_experiment/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Between July 2005 and July 2007, the Oregon Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants and Children program conducted the largest randomized field experiment (RFE) ever in the United States to assess the effectiveness of a low-cost peer counseling intervention to promote exclusive breastfeeding. We undertook a within-study comparison of the intervention using unique administrative data between July 2005 and July 2010. We found no difference between experimental and nonexperimental estimates but failed to determine correspondence based on more stringent criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Measuring and Reducing Selection Bias With a Quasi-Doubly Randomized Preference Trial</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/baruch_drpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/baruch_drpt/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Randomized experiments provide unbiased estimates of treatment effects, but are costly and time consuming. We demonstrate how a randomized experiment can be leveraged to measure selection bias by conducting a subsequent observational study that is identical in every way except that subjects choose their treatment—a quasi-doubly randomized preference trial (quasi-DRPT). Researchers first strive to think of and measure all possible confounders and then determine how well these confounders as controls can reduce or eliminate selection bias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does classroom time matter?</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/baruch_rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/baruch_rct/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Little experimental evidence exists on the causal impact of class time on academic performance when students have access to extensive course material online. We randomized 725 college students into traditional twice-per-week and compressed once-per-week lecture formats in introductory microeconomics. Students in the traditional format scored 3.2 out of 100 points higher (0.21 standard deviations) on the midterm than those in the compressed format but a statistically insignificant 1.6 points higher (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telephone peer counseling of breastfeeding among WIC participants: a randomized controlled trial</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/oregon_rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/oregon_rct/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We develop and assess the performance of an econometric prediction model that relies on administrative data held by international agencies to target over $380 million annually in unconditional cash transfers to Syrian refugees in Lebanon. Standard metrics of prediction accuracy suggest targeting using administrative data is comparable to a short-form Proxy Means Test, which requires a survey of the entire target population. We show that small differences in accuracy across approaches are largely attributable to a few data fields.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
