<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Posts on Onur Altindag</title>
    <link>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Posts on Onur Altindag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>©2023 Onur Altındağ · Cover photo: Bayt Beirut, 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onuraltindag.info/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Uphill Battle to Restore Democracy</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/elections2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/elections2023/</guid>
      <description>In less than 50 days, on May 14, Turkey will hold a pivotal election, with both presidential and parliamentary seats up for grabs. After 20 years of President Erdogan’s Islamist party’s rule, the united opposition has a real chance to unseat him and his party. While the presidential election has garnered much attention, the parliamentary race is just as crucial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karantinanın ruh sağlığına etkileri</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/karantina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/karantina/</guid>
      <description>Covid-19 ile  mücadele için alınan önlemler arasında psikolojik olarak belki de en ağır olanı karantina. Karantina yüksek risk grubundaki bireyleri daha fazla etkiliyor. Bu grup pandemi boyunca daha az hareket ediyor ve sosyal olarak kendini daha çok izole ediyor. Bu bireylerin mevcut sağlık durumunu toplum genelinden halihazırda daha kötü olduğu için,  hareketsizlik ve sosyal izolasyonun fiziksel ve ruh sağlığına etkisi daha da riskli bir konuma evriliyor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koronavirüs vefat sayıları ne anlatıyor?</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/excess_mortality_tr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/excess_mortality_tr/</guid>
      <description>Hepimizin takip ettiği ve Sağlık Bakanlığı tarafından açıklanan koronovirüs bağlantılı ölüm sayıları, tıbbi testlerle virüsü taşıdığı teyit edilmiş hastaların vefatlarını yansıtıyor. Türkiye de diğer ülkeler gibi tanı konmadan vefat etmiş hastaları bu istatistiklere dahil etmiyor. Bu nedenle, direkt ya da dolaylı yoldan koronavirüs nedeniyle ölen hasta sayısı, beyan edilen rakamların üstünde.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do official COVID19 death statistics tell us?</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/excess_mortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/blog/excess_mortality/</guid>
      <description>The Turkish Ministry of Health announces the death toll due to novel coronavirus cases on a daily basis. These statistics are based on confirmed COVID19 cases. Like other countries, Turkey does not include people who died without proper medical diagnoses into the official statistics. As such, the number of patients who died directly or indirectly due to COVID19 tend to be higher than the numbers in official statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
