<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Onur Altindag</title>
    <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Onur Altindag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>©2023 Onur Altındağ · Cover photo: Bayt Beirut, 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onuraltindag.info/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Short-lived Effects of Unconditional Cash Transfers to Refugees</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_rd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_rd/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We study two yearlong unconditional cash-based assistance programs for Syrian refugees in Lebanon, and show that they improve consumption, child well-being, food security, and reduce livelihood coping. Despite high transfer values, we find no evidence of lasting effects at six months after either program ends. Households spend transfers on basic needs, and take children out of work and re-enroll them in school. Beneficiaries increase cash savings and their stock of durable goods, but liquidate and spend these assets during or soon after the beneficiary period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Health Policy At Scale: Impact of a Government-sponsored Information Campaign on Infant Mortality in Denmark</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/denmark_sids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/denmark_sids/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We evaluate the impact of a nationwide public health intervention on deaths from sudden infant death syndrome (SIDS), using population data from Denmark in a regression discontinuity research design. The information campaign—implemented primarily through a universal nurse home visiting program—reduced infant mortality by 17.2 percent and saved between 11.6-13.5 lives over 10,000 births. The estimated effect sizes are 11-14 times larger among low birthweight and preterm infants relative to the overall population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Humanitarian Aid Using Administrative Data: Model Design and Validation</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/lebanon_uct_targeting/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We develop and assess the performance of an econometric prediction model that relies on administrative data held by international agencies to target over $380 million annually in unconditional cash transfers to Syrian refugees in Lebanon. Standard metrics of prediction accuracy suggest targeting using administrative data is comparable to a short-form Proxy Means Test, which requires a survey of the entire target population. We show that small differences in accuracy across approaches are largely attributable to a few data fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blessing or burden? Impacts of refugees on businesses and the informal economy</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_refugees_firms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_refugees_firms/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We study the impact of the sudden arrival of more than three million Syrian refugees in Turkey on Turkish businesses. Our empirical methodology exploits the annual variation in refugee outflows from Syria and geographic concentrations of Arabic-speaking communities in Turkey, which date back to the rupture of the Ottoman Empire after World War I. Using yearly firm census data from 2006 to 2015, we document that refugee inflows induced a positive impact on the intensive and extensive margins of firm production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Nonexperimental Methods Provide Unbiased Estimates of a Breastfeeding Intervention? A Within-Study Comparison of Peer Counseling in Oregon</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/oregon_non_experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/oregon_non_experiment/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Between July 2005 and July 2007, the Oregon Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants and Children program conducted the largest randomized field experiment (RFE) ever in the United States to assess the effectiveness of a low-cost peer counseling intervention to promote exclusive breastfeeding. We undertook a within-study comparison of the intervention using unique administrative data between July 2005 and July 2010. We found no difference between experimental and nonexperimental estimates but failed to determine correspondence based on more stringent criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of the Affordable Care Act Medicaid Expansion on Subjective Well-Being in the US Adult Population, 2010–2016</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/aca_medicaid_subjective_wellbeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/aca_medicaid_subjective_wellbeing/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Objectives. To determine whether the 2014 Affordable Care Act Medicaid expansion affected well-being in the low-income and general adult US populations. Methods. We obtained data from adults aged 18 to 64 years in the nationally representative Gallup-Sharecare Well-Being Index from 2010 to 2016 (n = 1 674 953). We used a difference-in-differences analysis to compare access to and difficulty affording health care and subjective well-being outcomes (happiness, sadness, worry, stress, and life satisfaction) before and after Medicaid expansion in states that did and did not expand Medicaid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judicial Bypass for Minors Obtaining an Abortion: Ten years of Data from Arkansas</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/arkansas_judicial_bypass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/arkansas_judicial_bypass/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Objectives. To describe demographic characteristics and abortion timing of minors in Arkansas who obtained an abortion through a judicial bypass, and to contrast the frequency of judicial bypass in other states in the United States.
Methods.We used individual-level data on all abortions to minors (n = 2624) performed in Arkansas from 2005 to 2014 and aggregated data from 10 additional states on abortions obtained through a judicial bypass. We characterized correlates of the judicial bypass and its association with the timing of abortion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Measuring and Reducing Selection Bias With a Quasi-Doubly Randomized Preference Trial</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/baruch_drpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/baruch_drpt/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Randomized experiments provide unbiased estimates of treatment effects, but are costly and time consuming. We demonstrate how a randomized experiment can be leveraged to measure selection bias by conducting a subsequent observational study that is identical in every way except that subjects choose their treatment—a quasi-doubly randomized preference trial (quasi-DRPT). Researchers first strive to think of and measure all possible confounders and then determine how well these confounders as controls can reduce or eliminate selection bias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Son Preference, Fertility Decline, and the Nonmissing Girls of Turkey</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_son_preference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/turkey_son_preference/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Couples in Turkey exhibit son preference through son-biased differential stopping behavior that does not cause a sex ratio imbalance in the population. Demand for sons leads to lower ratios of boys to girls in larger families but higher ratios in smaller families. Girls are born earlier than their male siblings, and son-biased fertility behavior is persistent in response to decline in fertility over time and across households with parents from different backgrounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does classroom time matter?</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/baruch_rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/baruch_rct/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Little experimental evidence exists on the causal impact of class time on academic performance when students have access to extensive course material online. We randomized 725 college students into traditional twice-per-week and compressed once-per-week lecture formats in introductory microeconomics. Students in the traditional format scored 3.2 out of 100 points higher (0.21 standard deviations) on the midterm than those in the compressed format but a statistically insignificant 1.6 points higher (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telephone peer counseling of breastfeeding among WIC participants: a randomized controlled trial</title>
      <link>https://onuraltindag.info/research/oregon_rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onuraltindag.info/research/oregon_rct/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We develop and assess the performance of an econometric prediction model that relies on administrative data held by international agencies to target over $380 million annually in unconditional cash transfers to Syrian refugees in Lebanon. Standard metrics of prediction accuracy suggest targeting using administrative data is comparable to a short-form Proxy Means Test, which requires a survey of the entire target population. We show that small differences in accuracy across approaches are largely attributable to a few data fields.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
